[{
    "question": "Where did the Great Fire of London begin, on 2 September 1666?",
    "choice1": "In Thomas Farriner’s bakery on Pudding Lane ",
    "choice2": "Bıg Ben",
    "choice3": "St. Paul's Cathedral",
    "choice4": "Tower of London",
    "answer": 1
},
 
{
   "question": "In World War 2 During Operation D-Day, Where Allied troops invaded ?",
    "choice1": "The Sudetenland",
    "choice2": "The Rhineland",
    "choice3": "Normandy",
    "choice4": "The Potomac",
    "answer": 3
},
{
    "question": "Which part of Berlin was enclosed by the wall?",
    "choice1": "East",
    "choice2": "South",
    "choice3": "North",
    "choice4": "West",
    "answer": 4
},
{
    "question": "Which  is not one of codenames used by Allied forces on D-Day?",
    "choice1": "Utah",
    "choice2": "Seattle",
    "choice3": "Omaha",
    "choice4": "Gold",
    "answer": 2
},
{
    "question": "What scandal forced U.S. President Richard Nixon to resign in 1974?",
    "choice1": "Iran Contra",
    "choice2": "Watergate",
    "choice3": "Lewinsky",
    "choice4": "Whitewater",
    "answer": 2
},
{
    "question": "Along with the United States, what other world power was a major player in the War of 1812?",
    "choice1": "Great Britain",
    "choice2": "Italy",
    "choice3": "Ottoman Empire",
    "choice4": "France",
    "answer": 1
},
{
    "question": "The Cuban Revolution led to the rise of what dictator?",
    "choice1": "Rajel Trujilo",
    "choice2": "Augusto Pinochet",
    "choice3": "Che Guevera",
    "choice4": "Fidel Castro",
    "answer": 4
},
{
    "question": "Who was the first female prime minister of Britain?",
    "choice1": "Margaret Thatcher",
    "choice2": "Florence Nightingale",
    "choice3": "Jane Austen",
    "choice4": "Queen Elizabeth II",
    "answer": 1
},
{
    "question": "What charter was passed by King John of England in 1215?",
    "choice1": "Mayflower Compact",
    "choice2": "Quartering Act",
    "choice3": "Magna Carta",
    "choice4": "Stamp Act",
    "answer": 3
},
{
    "question": "The Reign of Terror was a period during which major social  event?",
    "choice1": "American Revolution",
    "choice2": "Hatitian Revolution",
    "choice3": "Cuban Revolution",
    "choice4": "French Revolution",
    "answer": 4
},
{
    "question": "What military leader, rose to power during the French Revolution?",
    "choice1": "Louis XVI",
    "choice2": "Napoleon Bonaparte",
    "choice3": "Maximilien de Robespierre",
    "choice4": "Marquis de Lafayette",
    "answer": 2
},
{
    "question": "In which year did World War I start?",
    "choice1": "1912",
    "choice2": "1913",
    "choice3": "1914",
    "choice4": "1915",
    "answer": 3
},
{
    "question": "The Protestant Reformation was started by whom?",
    "choice1": "Francis Bacon",
    "choice2": "Voltaire",
    "choice3": "John Calvin",
    "choice4": "Martin Luther",
    "answer": 4
},
{
    "question": "Eva Peron was the first lady of what country?",
    "choice1": "Argentina",
    "choice2": "Peru",
    "choice3": "Brazil",
    "choice4": "Colombia",
    "answer": 1
},
{
    "question": "Which of these men was not an important figure during the Renaissance?",
    "choice1": "Adam Smith",
    "choice2": "Michelangelo",
    "choice3": "Francis Bacon",
    "choice4": "Leonardo da Vinci",
    "answer": 1
},
{
    "question": "Who was responsible for liberating much of South America?",
    "choice1": "Agustin de Iturbide",
    "choice2": "Simon Bolivar",
    "choice3": "Manuel Noriega",
    "choice4": "Charles III",
    "answer": 2
},
{
    "question": "Which Roman Emperor's Edict of Milan made Christianity legal?",
    "choice1": "Augustus",
    "choice2": "Marcus Aurelius",
    "choice3": "Nero",
    "choice4": "Constantine",
    "answer": 4
},
{
    "question": "What was the name of the first computer?",
    "choice1": "INIAC",
    "choice2": "CAINE",
    "choice3": "ENIAC",
    "choice4": "CNIEC",
    "answer": 3
},
{
    "question": "What African nation successfully resisted European colonialism in the late 19th century?",
   "choice1": "Ethiopia",
    "choice2": "Nigeria",
    "choice3": "Ghana",
    "choice4": "Cameroon",
    "answer": 1
},
{
    "question": " Who wrote The Communist Manifesto?",
    "choice1": "Karl Marx",
    "choice2": "both Marx and Engels",
    "choice3": "Friedrich Engels",
    "choice4": "Charles Darwin",
    "answer": 2
}
]
